https://crosier.org/privacy-policy-2/

Privacy Policy
Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have developed this Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate and disclose, and make use of personal information. The following outlines our privacy policy.About UsThe Crosiers are members of the Canons Regular of the Order of the Holy Cross, one the Roman Catholic Church’s oldest religious orders. We are priests and brothers who live together according to the Rule of St. Augustine. Our charism consists of life in a community setting, daily prayer and ministry. The U.S. conventual priory is headquartered in Phoenix, Arizona; we have houses in Phoenix and in Onamia, Minnesota. For more information, visit our About Us – Overview page.What Information We GatherWe may gather certain information, either personal or anonymous, based on your activities or data submitted while browsing our website, in the following formats.Form informationIf you submit a contact form, mailing list signup form, or donation form on our website, we collect any personal data submitted by you (Name, Email Address, and for any payment forms, cardholder information).Statistical informationOur website uses the following tools to collect statistical information about browsing behavior and device or browser information, in order to improve the experience of our website:Google Analytics (Governed by Google’s Privacy Policy)Google Recaptcha (Governed by Google’s Privacy Policy and Terms of Use)To opt out of Google Analytics data collection, you can install this tool.Google Recaptcha will only collect data upon form submission. By submitting a form, you consent to Google’s terms of use regarding Recaptcha, as dictated in their privacy policy (linked above).Cookie informationWe collect cookies, both directly and through trusted third-parties, in order to improve the performance and user experience on our website. Please see our Cookie Policy for more information on usage and to manage your cookie settings.Embedded content from other websitesContent on this site may occasionally include embedded content (e.g. videos, hosted forms). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.Crosiers uses the following platform to embed content:YouTube (governed by Google’s Privacy Policy)Constant Contact (Privacy Policy)Blackbaud (Privacy Policy)These platforms may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that third-party website.LinksWe may provide links to third-party websites, such as those of other regional order websites. While on these sites, they may collect information about you. Because we do not control the information policies or practices of these third party websites, you should review their privacy policies to learn more about how they collect and use personally identifiable information.How We Use Your InformationWe may use your personal information when we have a valid reason to do so. Such instances may include:To process and respond to a directly submitted inquiry or request;To process a donation;To add you to our mailing list upon form submission;To personalize services in order to provide a better user experience;To improve our website experience.You have the right to request that we cease to use or store your information. See the “Accessing your data” section for more information.How We Protect Your InformationWe take the greatest care in the security of your submitted information. Our website uses up-to-date Secure Socket Layers (SSL) encryption in order to protect the transmission of your data upon submission to our servers.Where your information is storedDepending on the type of information you have submitted, your data will either be stored securely in a database on our server; or in the database of one of our trusted third-party partners. These third-party partners include:Constant Contact – for email mailing list subscriptions;Google – for anonymous statistical information, and/or personalized data (for visitors from outside the EU);Blackbaud – for inquiries and donations submitted on our website.Information stored by these third-parties is protected by and subject to their individual privacy policies. You can find their policies at the links below:Constant Contact   Google    BlackbaudInternational TransfersDue to the multinational locations of our servers, as well as the servers of our third-party partners, any information which you consented to provide may be transferred to a location outside of the country or region you are located in. Data will only be transferred to either:a) our servers;b) trusted third-party partners, as indicated in the above section, which we determine to have adequate transparency and security parameters in place for the protection, storage and accessibility of your data.Data breach preventionOur servers and website infrastructure are kept up to date and secured by a Web Application Firewall (WAF) to protect against a data breach via a third party attack.In the unlikely event of a breach where your stored data is, or may have been compromised, we will inform you within 24 hours after becoming aware of the data breach, and provide you with our action(s) taken in order to protect your data moving forward.Note that due to a multitude of different vulnerabilities which are present during the submission of data and are outside of our control (local computer viruses, unsecured/compromised internet connections, etc.), we cannot guarantee and are not responsible for compromised data which occurs during the submission of data and as the result of such factors outside of our control. However, once the data has been submitted and is stored in our infrastructure, we ensure that the data is responsibly held and secured.Data Controller & Data Protection OfficerThe data controller is the organization/entity responsible for the protection of information on and submitted to this website. The data controller is Director of Communications. Complaints, concerns or requests will be fielded by the Data Protection Officer who can be reached by filling out a request on this form.How Long We Store Your Data ForPersonal information submitted directly on our website through a form is stored in our database indefinitely, or until manual deletion is requested.Data collected by Google for statistical and personalization purposes is retained for 50 months  before being deleted automatically. More information about Google’s data retention policy can be found here.Accessing Your DataIf you have submitted data on our site, you have the right to access, change or request erasion of this data at any time. Please fill out this form to request a file of your submitted personal data. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you via this form.GoogleOur data collected via Google Analytics is anonymized and therefore not personally traceable to you unless you are signed into your account. If you have a Google account, you can request a copy of your information from Google here.Our Cookie PolicyWe use cookies to personalize content, to analyze our traffic, provide additional features, and improve your experience on our website. We also share information about your use of our site with trusted third-party partners who may combine it with other information that you’ve provided to them or that they’ve collected from your use of their services.In order to see the cookies we use, or to change your cookie settings, view our Cookie Policy.Changing your cookie settingsYou can adjust your cookie settings or withdraw your consent on our Cookie Policy page.Changes To This PolicyAny changes to this Policy will be posted directly on this page. We will also inform you when we make these changes, and what changes were made below.Previous changes to this policySept 17, 2020: Released privacy policy.
We are Crosiers
We are priests and brothers who live together according to the Rule of St. Augustine. Our charism consists of life in a community setting, daily prayer and ministry.
Learn More
content
About Us
Worship Services
Phoenix Community
Onamia Community
St. Odilia
Your Support
Vocations
Contact Us
site info
Privacy Policy
Terms-and-Conditions
keep in touch
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.OkNoPrivacy policy
